Guide to the Asian CineVision Records TAM.416
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Video Recordings
  - Video 259: CCTV, November 2, 1980; Cuid9305 (Box 95, Video Cuid9305)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature on the 1980 presidential election and a report on the New York City marathon. In the first part, various Chinatown activities that support different candidates are featured, including a public assembly to support Reagan for president, President Jimmy Carter's visit to Chinatown, and interviews with Chinese American representatives who actively participate in campaigning. The host also interviews Virginia M. Kee () who is running for Democratic representative in New York State. Instructions on how to cast a vote are also given. The end of this program includes a coverage of the 1980 New York City marathon on October 26, with the starting point in Staten Island.
  - Video 260: CCTV, November 9, 1980; Cuid9306 (Box 95, Video Cuid9306)
    This episode contains two parts: a report on a Chinese acrobatic group's performance, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part covers a Guangdong acrobatic troupe's US tour. An interview with the troupe leader and highlights of the troupe's acrobatic performance are included. The second part is an Allen Fong () film The Wild Child () (1977). The film depicts the life of a young boy who lives with his grandmother in a rural village.
  - Video 261: CCTV, November 16, 1980; Cuid9307 (Box 95, Video Cuid9307)
    This episode contains three parts: a report on a Chinatown community gathering, interviews with Hong Kong celebrities, and a feature on a Hong Kong performance troupe. The first part is a community gathering at the Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association. The purpose of the gathering is to collect opinions from Chinatown residents on the newly elected President Ronald Reagan. The second part of the episode includes interviews with two Hong Kong celebrities - singer Chelsia Chan Chau Ha () and Cantonese opera performer Chan Leung Chung (). The third part features Hong Kong Chor Fung Ming Cantonese Opera troupe ()'s operatic performances in the United States. Also included in this part are interviews with leading performers: Siu Chung-kwan (), Lung Kim Sang (), Mui Suet Sze (), Chu Kim Tang () and Yin Suet Fun (), and with troupe manager: So Siu-Tong (),Wong Har-wai ().
  - Video 262: CCTV, November 30, 1980; Cuid9308 (Box 95, Video Cuid9308)
    This episode includes two parts: a report on a martial arts contest, and a 35-minute film. The first part covers a 1980 martial arts competition held at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. Interviews with the first-place winner and the competition's organizer are included. The second part features a Curtis Choy film Dupont Guy: The Schiz of Grant Avenue (1976). The film narrates the struggles and experiences of being Chinese American.
  - Video 263: CCTV, December 14, 1980; Cuid9309 (Box 95, Video Cuid9309)
    This episode includes three parts: a report on a Chinese exhibition, a report on the death of John Lennon, and a theatrical production. The first section covers The 1980 Exhibition of People' Republic of China held at the New York Coliseum in New York City. Participants include Ed Koch, Mayor of New York City, Chai Zemin (), Chinese Ambassador to the United States of America Ambassador, and Lai Yali (), Deputy Permanent Representative of China to the United Nations. Over a thousand people attend. On display are Chinese electronic products and cultural artifacts. The second part covers the death of John Lennon in New York City, a member of the British rock band The Beatles. The third section features a Chinese theatrical production, Old Soldier (), a co-produced by CCTV and the New York Drama Society.
  - Video 264: CCTV, December 21, 1980; Cuid9310 (Box 95, Video Cuid9310)
    This episode includes two parts: a cultural program about Christmas and a television drama produced by CCTV. The first part covers Christmas activities in New York City and includes street interviews with people on their Christmas plans. The second part is a special program called "Asian American Experience" featuring a New York Shakespeare Festival Workshop of FOB. The play is written by David Henry Hwang, starring Calvin Jung, John Lone, and Ginny Yang. The third section is a single-episode television romance drama Autumn Dream () produced by CCTV Production and Performance workshop students.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 48 minutes
  - Video 265: CCTV, December 28, 1980; Cuid9311 (Box 95, Video Cuid9311)
    This episode includes two parts: a special program on John Lennon, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part pays tribute to John Lennon, a member of British rock band The Beatles who had recently been murdered in front of his apartment building in Manhattan, New York City. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 266: CCTV, January 4, 1981; Cuid9312 (Box 95, Video Cuid9312)
    This episode shows the 1980 martial arts competition held at The Yung Wing Public School in Chinatown. Interviews with the first-place winner and the competition's organizer are included.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 56 minutes
  - Video 267: CCTV, January 25, 1981; cuid9313 (Box 96, Video Cuid9313)
    This episode contains three parts: a documentary, a feature on a martial arts performance, and street interviews. The first part is a special program called Asian American Experience in which a documentary about the historical exclusion and mistreatment of Asian Americans in the United States is shown. The second part features a martial arts performance held at the Murry Bergtraum High School. The third part includes street interviews with people about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 268: CCTV, February 1, 1981; cuid9314 (Box 96, Video cuid9314)
    This episode contains two parts: news coverage, and a social service program. The first part is a program called Times Magazine, which covers international, national, local and Chinatown news. The local news includes the robbery of a Chinatown jewel store, the progress of labor-employer negotiation in Chinatown's Silver Palace Restaurant, and information about a free physical examination program available to Chinatown residents. The second is called At Your Service (), which introduces culinary and English lessons offered by China Institute. Interviews with the institute's organizer and lesson participants are included.
  - Video 269: CCTV, 1981-02-15; cuid9315 (Box 96)
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 60 min., Preservation Note: The tape could not be digitized due to advanced degradation.
  - Video 270: CCTV, March 1, 1981; Cuid2604 (Box 96, Video Cuid2604)
    This episode includes two parts: news coverage and a social service program. The first part is a news program called Times Magazine which covers international, national, local and Chinatown news. Local news cover an anniversary performance by Chinatown's Four Sea Players is held at Pace University. The second part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and make-up skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan gives a makeup demonstration.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic Video, Duration: 60 minutes
  - Video 271: CCTV, March 8, 1981; Cuid2605 (Box 96, Video Cuid2605)
    This episode includes two parts: a feature report on a Chinese American politician and a theatrical production. The first part is a feature report on Anna Chan Chennault (), spouse of American military aviator major general Claire Lee Chennault. She attends a Chinese American event and talks about her recent visits to Beijing, People's Republic of China, and Taipei, Republic of China (Taiwan). Her visits to Asia is on behalf of the Ronald Reagan administration. The second section features Chinese drama play Old Soldier (), a co-production by CCTV and the New York Drama Society.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 55 minutes
  - Video 272: CCTV, March 15, 1981; Cuid2606 (Box 96, Video Cuid2606)
    This episode contains three parts: news coverage, a report on a Chinatown tenant-landlord dispute, and a feature report on ethnic discrimination in the United States. The first part is a CCTV news report which covers international, national, and local news. The second part is a report about a dispute between Chinatown tenants and the landlord called Thomas Sung (). The third part features the history and current status of Chinese Americans and Asian Americans being discriminated against and stereotyped. The feature starts from the launch of a Yves Saint Laurent produced perfume called Opium. Interviews with experts and clips from the documentary The Fist of Righteous Harmony are also included. The host criticizes discrimination and stereotypes.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 31 minutes
  - Video 273: CCTV, March 22, 1981; cuid2607 (Box 96, Video cuid2607)
    This episode includes three parts: a report on a protest, news coverage, and a 26-minute film. The first part covers a boycott campaign against the launch of the film Charlie Chan: The Curse of Dragon Queen. Street interviews with people about their opinion on the film and on the boycott are included. The second part is CCTV news report which covers international, national and local news. Local news covered includes a subway workers' strike in New York City, and the New York Police Department's massive search for and arrest of a suspect allegedly involved in murdering three CBS employees. Interviews with two New York policemen are included. The third part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 59 minutes
  - Video 274: CCTV, May 1981; Cuid9316 (Box 96, Video Cuid9316)
    This episode features three documentaries. The first is WFAA Production's Welcome to America about Vietnamese refugees' life in the United States, directed by Jerry Cadigan and first aired on October 10, 1979. The second is a WNET/Thirteen documentary called New Immigrants, documenting the struggles and anxieties of Korean immigrants in New York City. The third is a 5-minute excerpt from the 1979 Academy Award-winning film From Mao to Mozart: Isaac Stern in China, directed by Allan Miller.
  - Video 275: CCTV, July 14, 1981; Cuid9317 (Box 96, Video Cuid9317)
    This episode includes five parts: news reports, a report on a social service club, a report on a film festival, an excerpt of a Hong Kong film, and segments of a puppet show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The second part covers the inauguration ceremony of the 1981-82 leadership of Lions Club Chinatown. The third part features highlights of the 1971 Asian American Film Festival. The fourth part of the episode showcases an excerpt of Hong Kong film Dangerous Encounter - 1st Kind () (1980), directed by Tsui Hark (). The last section features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe originated from Fujian Province, People's Republic of China.
  - Video 276: CCTV, July 19, 1981; Cuid15041 (Box 97, Video Cuid15041)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a feature. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week, highlighting the Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival. The second part features a boycott campaign against the launch of film Charlie Chan: The Curse of Dragon Queen Also included are street interviews with people about their opinion on the film and on the boycott.
  - Video 277: CCTV, July 26, 1981; Cuid15042 (Box 97, Video Cuid15042)
    This episode includes four parts: news reports, an interview with a Hong Kong celebrity, a protest, and a segment of a Chinese animation film. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes a protest by African Americans who demand job opportunities. The protest is held at a construction site on Madison Avenue in New York City. The second part is an interview with Doris Law () who is a former Miss Hong Kong Pageant recipient. The third part covers a rally at Lincoln Center in New York City, protesting against budget cuts for the arts. Interviews with participating artists are included. The last part of the program shows a segment of a Chinese animated film Prince Nezha's Triumph Against Dragon King () (1979).
  - Video 278: CCTV, August 2, 1981; Cuid15043 (Box 97, Video Cuid15043)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports, and an interview with a Hong Kong film director. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week including the 1980 United States census results on the population of Chinese Americans. The population numbers were more than 800,000, which exceeded the population of other Asian ethnicities. The second part features an interview with Hong Kong film director Tsui Hark (). Clips from Tsui Hark's films are also included.
  - Video 279: CCTV, August 9, 1981; Cuid15044 (Box 97, Video Cuid15044)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature on a Chinese performance troupe, and coverage of a cultural festival. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The second part features Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's visit to New York; performances and interviews are included. The third part highlights the Third Asian/Pacific American Heritage Festival, which was held in Lincoln Center on May 2, 1981.
  - Video 280: CCTV, August 16, 1081; Cuid15045 (Box 97, Video Cuid15045)
    This episode includes two parts: a news report, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part includes extensive coverage of international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In the local news section, the host announces the changes and current status of Chinese American population in the country. The announcement is based on the 1980 United States census. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 281: CCTV, August 23, 1981; Cuid15046 (Box 97, Video Cuid15046)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the Beautifying Chinatown () project is covered. Street interviews in Chinatown are included. The local news also features an anti-eviction movement in Chinatown. Interviews with organizers from Asian Americans For Equality and building management personnel are included. Highlights from Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's performance in New York City are also showcased.
  - Video 282: CCTV, August 30, 1981; Cuid15047 (Box 97, Video Cuid15047)
    This episode includes news reports that extensively cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news features a unionization movement organized by Chinese restaurant workers in midtown New York City. Local news also includes an award presentation ceremony organized by International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) which presents scholarships to children of Chinese American union members. At last, a martial art contest is featured.
  - Video 283: CCTV, September 6, 1981; Cuid15048 (Box 97, Video Cuid15048)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes the New York City mayoral election campaigns in Chinatown. Interviews with two candidates, Frank Barbaro and Ed Koch, are included. This episode also includes interviews with Chinese Americans who will run for district representatives as Democrats. The last section of the episode includes street interviews with people about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 284: CCTV, September 13, 1981; Cuid15049 (Box 97, Video Cuid15049)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news features, the Labor Day parade in New York City, which celebrates the hundred-year anniversary of the establishment of labor unionization is highlighted. The episode also features the opening ceremony of the Products Exhibition of Jiangsu Province organized at Sino-American Commodities Center.
  - Video 285: CCTV, September 20, 1981; Cuid15050 (Box 98, Video Cuid15050)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the Labor Day parade in New York City celebrating the hundred-year anniversary of the establishment of labor unionization is covered. For the first time, Chinese American labor unions join the parade. Interviews with union leaders and members are included. News about the Peng Teng Restaurant labor strike is covered. The episode also features the opening ceremony of the Products Exhibition of Jiangsu Province organized at Sino-American Commodities Center.
  - Video 286: CCTV, October 4, 1981; Cuid15051 (Box 98, Video Cuid15051)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a current affairs forum. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes an interview with a Chinatown tenant who suffers from shortage of hot water and heating. Highlights from the Asian American Festival are also included. The second part is a current affairs forum called Fact? Debate? (??). In this episode, a campaign opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. The representative from Community Board No. 3 (Manhattan), Virginia M. Kee, and the representative from Asian Americans For Equality, Doris Koo, express their opinions.
  - Video 287: CCTV, October 11, 1981; Cuid15052 (Box 98, Video Cuid15052)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a social service program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news features a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Chinatown residents and Asian Americans For Equality demand a public hearing in the Chinatown community. The episode also includes a feature report introducing the history of services provided by the New York Public Library Chinatown branch located at 33 East Broadway, New York City. The second part is a program called At Your Service () in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The Chinatown Daycare Center, founded in 1969, faces financial burden and will be demolished by the state government.
  - Video 288: CCTV, October 18, 1981; Cuid15053 (Box 98, Video Cuid15053)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a travel program, and a Chinese puppet show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. A history of early Chinese immigrants in the United States is featured. The second part is a program called Travelogue () in which Orchard Crest farm in New Jersey is introduced. The third part features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe which originated in Fujian Province, People's Republic of China.
  - Video 289: CCTV, October 25, 1981; Cuid15054 (Box 98, Video Cuid15054)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a dance show, and a travel program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news includes coverage of a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Interviews with Chinatown residents being evicted are included. The episode also introduces the first generation Chinese typing computer. The second part shows performance highlights from the Chinese Dance Company of N.Y. Performances include Chinese folk dance, classic dance and martial art dance. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), which covers Sheepshead Bay in New York City, New York state.
  - Video 290: CCTV, November 1, 1981; Cuid15055 (Box 98, Video Cuid15055)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a cultural show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news includes coverage of a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Also included in this episode is a segment on a public hearing held by Community Board No. 3 (Manhattan) to discuss the Special Manhattan Bridge District with Chinatown residents. Opinions by politicians, Chinatown residents and activists are expressed. The second part shows performances from the Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival.
  - Video 291: CCTV, November 8, 1981; Cuid15056 (Box 98, Video Cuid15056)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature on a choir, and the arrival of a Chinese opera troupe. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, debts carried by the Chinatown Daycare Center are taken over by the Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association. The second part features performances by a Chinese choir in New York City. The third part features Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's visit to New York.
  - Video 292: CCTV, November 14, 1981; Cuid15057 (Box 98, Video Cuid15057)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature report on a university information event, and a social service program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, a Chinatown physician and nurse are interviewed on how to cope with disease in the winter season; the shortage of healthcare among Chinese community is mentioned. The second part features a university information session called College Day organized by the East Coast Asian Student Union. Student representatives from different universities are interviewed. The third part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and makeup skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan holds a makeup demonstration.
  - Video 293: CCTV, November 22, 1981; Cuid15058 (Box 98, Video Cuid15058)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, an interview with a Chinese artist, and an interview with a martial arts master. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, a new drama is presented by the Pan Asian Repertory. The second part features an interview with Chinese sculptor Situ Jie (). The third part includes an interview with a martial arts master and his students. A demonstration of Chinese traditional lion dancing performance is also included.
  - Video 294: CCTV, November 29, 1981; Cuid15059 (Box 99, Video Cuid15059)
    This video includes four parts: news reports, a feature on a Chinese painter, a television drama, and an interview. First, the news bulletin includes extensive coverage of international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the testimony Japanese Americans recounting being forcibly removed from their homes and mistreated by the U.S. government during World War II. The local news also includes the graduation dinner of CCTV's sixth session of the Production and Performance Workshop. The second part is a feature on Chinese painter Zhu Shengguang (). The third part is a television drama production called Nightmare, a collective production by students from CCTV's Production and Performance workshop. The fourth part features a martial arts master who specializes in Wing Chun.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 61 minutes.
  - Video 295: CCTV, December 13, 1981; Cuid15060 (Box 99, Video Cuid15060)